honestly.com 2019-12-07

# Privacy | Honestly

Honestly MT GmbH  
Hansaring 68-70  
50670 Köln  
Phone number: [+49 221 6430 7890 ](tel://+4922164307890)  
E-mail address: [kontakt@honestly.de](mailto:kontakt@honestly.de)  
Fax number: [+49 221 6430 7899](tel://+4922164307899)  
Authorized managing director: Sven Bläse, Mateo Freudenthal

Register Court: Cologne Local Court Register Number: HRB 84298 USt-IdNr.: DE284320814

Responsible for content according to § 55 Abs. 2 RStV:  
Sven Bläse (address as above)

Disclaimer:  
Despite careful content control, we assume no liability for the content of external links. The operators of the linked pages are solely responsible for their content.

## Data privacy policy

Honestly offers companies software solutions for customer and employee surveys. We would like to inform you about the handling of your personal data below. We comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as well as the German data protection regulations defined in the Teleservices Act (TMG) and the Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG). The safe handling of our customer’s data is a basic building block of our company and is of the highest priority to us.

Information, deletion, blocking  
You can receive information about the personal data we have stored about you as well as the origin, the recipient, and the purpose of data collection and data processing, at any time and free of charge. In addition, you have the right to request the correction, blocking, or deletion of your data. This does not apply to data that are stored due to legal regulations or required for the proper conduct of business. For data blocking to be realised at any time, data are kept in a lock file for control purposes. For all questions and concerns regarding the correction, blocking, or deletion of personal data, please contact our data protection officer using the contact details stated at the end of this privacy policy or at the address stated in the imprint. You also have the right to withdraw your consent to the processing of your data.

###  For everyone

####  Our website

We get in touch with customers and interested parties through our website. We only store access data such as the name of your internet service provider, the website from which you visited us, or the name of the requested file. These data are evaluated solely for the purpose of improving our offer and do not allow any inference to your person.

Personal data will be collected if you voluntarily provide this to us as part of a registration for our newsletter, a registration for a trial version, or a registration for a demo. Without your explicit consent, we only use the information you have provided to host our software and to contact you. When registering for the newsletter, your e-mail address will be used exclusively for advertising purposes until you unsubscribe from the newsletter. Unsubscribing is possible at any time. You will also find a corresponding link in each newsletter.

Employee engagement test account or customer experience demo  
When you sign up for a trial account for our Honestly Engage App, your name, e-mail address, as well as the name and size of your business will be stored in our CRM system (Hubspot). These data refer exclusively to the contact person. No data of other employees or customers are requested or collected.

These data are used exclusively to establish contact and assign orders. In addition, they will be forwarded to Pandadoc to create an offer for you. The data will only be forwarded to carefully selected companies with whom we have a data processing agreement (DPA). It is of great importance to us that our subcontractors also handle your data conscientiously. The data are not resold.

For more information about HubSpot's privacy policy, please see:  
<https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy>  
Address: 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141, United States

For more information about Pandadoc’s Privacy Policy, please see:  
<https://www.pandadoc.com/privacy-policy/>  
Address: 153 Kearny St 94108, San Francisco, United States

By creating a trial account (for customer experience or employee engagement), you consent to Honestly using the data described above for the purposes of providing the service.

##### Use of cookies

We use cookies on our website. These small text files are stored on the browser of your PC on request. They help us to customize the content and the format of our website to your needs for the future. We do not use cookies to place damaging programs or spyware onto your computer. You can also use our website without the use of cookies, which may limit or affect some presentations and features of our offer. If you wish to deactivate the cookies, you can do this through special settings for your browser. Please use help functions to make the appropriate changes. You can manage online advertisement cookies through the following links: <http://www.aboutads.info/choices> for the USA and [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices ](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) for Europe.  
Of course, if you have activated the Do-Not-Track function on your browser, we will not store any data. However, with your permission to place cookies, you help us to continuously improve our website and our offer.

##### SSL encryption

Our website uses SSL encryption when it comes to the transmission of all data and content of our users. This encryption is activated, for example, in the processing of payments and requests that you make to us through our website. Please make sure that the SSL encryption is activated on your side during activities. The use of encryption is easy to recognize: The display in your browser line changes from "http: //" to "https: //". SSL-encrypted data cannot be read by third parties. Only submit your confidential information when SSL encryption is activated and contact us in case of doubt.

##### Google Analytics

We use the web analytics service Google Analytics from Google Inc. on our website, which uses cookies. These text files allow an analysis of your user behaviour regarding our website. The cookies generate information that is transmitted to a Google server. These servers are typically located in the USA, but they are based on usage agreements with the European Economic Area and truncate your IP address before it is sent to the USA. Only in exceptional cases is the IP address truncated after transfer to the USA. Google evaluates the information and provides other services in this context for us as website operators. The IP address is not combined with other Google services. By changing your browser settings, you can prevent the storage of cookies on your computer; however, this may be associated with display and functional restrictions when using our website. A browser plugin also prevents the collection and use of the data generated by the cookies. You can download it underthe following link: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices)  
Learn more about the privacy policies of Google and Google Analytics here: <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html>[<](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/de.html)  
or <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/>.

##### Google AdWords

With Google AdWords, we use an online advertising program provided by Google Inc. on our website. This also includes conversion tracking. With this tool, Google AdWords places a cookie on your PC if you visit our website through a Google ad. The cookie is invalid after 30 days. It has no personal traceability. If you visit our website as a user and the cookie is still working, we, together with Google, become aware that you have clicked on the corresponding advertisement and have been redirected to our website. Each Google AdWords customer is assigned a different cookie. Cookies are thus not traceable via the websites of the advertisers. Data gathered through conversion cookies are used to generate conversion statistics for advertisers. We, as customers, find out the total number of users who engaged with our advertisement and were then diverted to a web page that was tagged with a conversion tracking tag. We do not receive any information in this process that could personally identify you as a user. If you object to the tracking process, you can deactivate the cookie of the Google conversion tracking system on your browser. If you need to, use the help function of the browser for further information. For more information about Google's privacy policy, please visit <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.

##### Further service providers

In addition, we forward your first name and surname, your e-mail address, and, if applicable, your IP address to the following service providers for statistical purposes in regular intervals:  
Intercom, Inc.  
If you voluntarily give your contact information to us through our chat operator Intercom, it will be stored in both Intercom and Hubspot. This serves to contact customers or prospective customers and allows us to respond to customer requests or problems.  
For more information about the privacy policy of Intercom, Inc., see:  
<https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy>  
Address: 55 2nd St, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA

HubSpot, Inc.  
If you register for an employee engagement test access or customer experience demo through our website, your name, e-mail address, as well as the size and name of your company will be stored in Hubspot. This serves for communication, consultation, and cooperation with customers and prospective customers, and allows us to respond to their needs individually.  
For more information about the privacy policy of HubSpot, see:  
<https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy>  
Address: 25 First Street, 2nd Floor, Cambridge, MA 02141, United States

Pandadoc, Inc.  
If we send you an offer at your request, your data will automatically be forwarded from HubSpot to Pandadoc, in order to create an offer.  
For more information about the privacy policy of Pandadoc, see: <https://www.pandadoc.com/privacy-policy/>[<](https://www.pandadoc.com/privacy-policy/)  
Address: 153 Kearny St 94108, San Francisco, United States

We these services to improve our service and to process your support requests faster and more efficiently. The three companies listed above have joined the "EU-US Privacy Shield", which is reviewed annually by the EU and aims to provide a higher level of data protection for non-EU companies. We have signeda dataprocessing agreement (DPA) with these foreign-based companies. This is based on the highest standard of data protection.

By using the Honestly website, you consent to the transfer and storage of your data to these companies, and the use thereof in the manner described.

####  Our blog

Twitter Plugin  
Exclusively for our blog, we use functions of the microblogging service Twitter on our website. The operator of Twitter is Twitter Inc. The company is based in the United States, San Francisco, CA 94103, 1355 Market St, Suite 900. The main function of Twitter is the "Tweet function". If you use this function via our website, it will be linked to your Twitter account. Data exchange with other users and the transfer of data to Twitter is possible. We are not aware of the content of the data sent to Twitter, nor are we informed about its utilization. Find out more about this at <http://twitter.com/privacy>. You can find Twitter’s detailed privacy policy there. Furthermore, the platform offers you the opportunity to create your own privacy settings via [http ://twitter.com/account/settings.](http://twitter.com/account/settings).

Facebook Plugin  
Exclusively for our blog, you will find plugins of the social network Facebook on our website. Its provider is Facebook Inc. It is based in the USA, California 94025, 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park. The Facebook logo or the "Like-Button" on our site make the Facebook plug-ins recognizable for you. There is an overview of the Facebook plugins at <http://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>.  
When you visit our website and click on the Facebook icon, we connect directly to the Facebook server via the plugin. You are then redirected there via your browser. Facebook then knows that you have visited our website with your IP address. With a click on the Facebook "Like-Button" you link content of our website to your Facebook profile. Facebook can connect the visit to our page with your user account. We are not aware of the nature of the content that is transmitted to Facebook and how Facebook uses it. For more information about data collection and use, see the Facebook privacy policy at <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. You can prevent the connection of your visit on our website with your Facebook profile by simply logging out of your Facebook account.

LinkedIn Plugin  
Exclusively for our blog, you will find plugins of the social network LinkedIn on our website. Its provider is LinkedIn Inc. It is in 2029 Stierlin Ct. Ste. 200 Mountain View, CA 94043, United States. The LinkedIn logo is clearly recognizable as such. When you share an article on our blog on LinkedIn, you link content from our website to your profile on LinkedIn. LinkedIn can connect the visit to our page with your user account. We are not aware of the nature of the content that is transmitted to LinkedIn and how LinkedIn uses it. For more information about data collection and use, see the LinkedIn privacy policy: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>

Disqus Plugin  
Exclusively for our blog, you will find plugins from Disqus on our website. Its provider is Disqus, Inc., headquarters: 717 Market St., San Francisco, CA 94103, United States. Disqus makes it possible to leave comments on our blogs and positively rate articles. If you comment on or post an article on our blog, Disqus may store information such as your IP address. For more information about data collection and use, see the Disqus privacy policy: [https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy"](https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy)

###  For companies, their employees and customers

#### General Information

Feedback terminals and web feedback form  
Our terminals serve for the easy collection of feedback. Personal data are collected if you provide them in the feedback form. Filling in these data is voluntary. If, for example, you provide a mobile phone number or e-mail address, this will be used by our customers to contact you. This is for the purpose of providing more details about your feedback to better meet your needs. The precise purpose of the data collection is specified in the respective contact form.

If you order an Honestly terminal, your data will be forwarded to the freight company commissioned with the delivery, insofar as this is necessary for the delivery of the goods. To process payments, we pass on your payment data to the bank responsible for the payment.

If you voluntarily enter your contact data into a feedback form, you consent to Honestly forwarding this information to the company to which you have provided feedback.

Manager app  
No personal data are collected via our Manager app. Only the results of the collected feedback are shown. To log into your Manager app account, you need your e-mail address and the password of your web account.

Deletion of personal data  
Upon complete processing of the contract and full payment of the purchase price, your data will be blocked for further use and deleted after expiry of the tax and commercial retention periods, unless you have deliberately consented to the further use of your data.

Data security  
After you have logged into our website with your access data, into our app or with a terminal, you can access the collected data. Communication and transmission of data via our server is always encrypted. Particularly all payment data is encrypted between you and us. Please note that access by third parties cannot be excluded to one hundred per cent. For your own safety, we recommend that you log out before leaving the website and close the browser window. Please also ensure that no third parties are aware of your login credentials.

#### Employee Engagement

Honestly always enters into a data processing agreement (DPA) with participating companies to ensure that both parties securely handle employee feedback. Feedback from company employees is encrypted and transmitted to our servers and made available to the company. Honestly ensures that companies can no longer link this feedback with individual employees.

Personal data provided to us by participating companies  
To participate as an active user in Honestly surveys, the company provides a list of employee names and e-mail addresses to Honestly. Optionally, additional metadata such as department, gender, or location are provided. Through this information, the employees are registered into the feedback system as users. The data are only used to send surveys to employees to ensure that each user only participates in each survey once, and to allow analysis of the collected metadata. The collected data are processed internally for analysis purposes. Employee data of our customers are never passed on to third parties by Honestly.

Engage app  
With the Honestly Engage app, companies can easily conduct continuous pulse surveys and/or one-time surveys among their employees. This feedback can be evaluated in real-time via the Honestly Manager app and the Honestly web application.

The Engage app can be downloaded from the Google Play Store or the Apple Store. To log into the network of your own company, users must previously have been entered (as described above) into the system. Then, by logging in once, they can easily take part in surveys with their company e-mail via their smartphone. Feedback via mobile phones will not save any other personal data. We do not access any other services on your private device. If you voluntarily enter personal information into a feedback form, you consent to Honestly passing this information on to the company to which you provided feedback.

The Engage App's anonymized usage data and error logs are sent to Fabric.io (belonging to Google LLC) on a regular basis to continually improve the app and identify and fix potential errors. Employee data or feedback data from the employees are not transferred.

For more information about the privacy policy of Fabric.io, see:  
<https://docs.fabric.io/apple/fabric/data-privacy.html>  
Address: Google LLC. Headquarters: 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043

By submitting feedback through the engage app, feedback terminal, or through our web feedback form (e-mail link), you consent to Honestly anonymously collecting, storing, and forwarding your feedback to your company.

####  Customer experience

Customer surveys are usually anonymous. Every customer can take part in surveys via the terminal or link. Data is only collected if the customer voluntarily enters them into the feedback form (for example, to contact them).

If you voluntarily enter your contact data into a feedback form, you consent to Honestly forwarding this information to the company to which you have provided feedback.

###  Contact information

Regulating authority

The regulating authority responsible for Honestly is:

State Representative for Data Protection and Freedom of Information North Rhine-Westphalia  
PO Box 20 04 44  
40102 Dusseldorf, Germany

Tel.: +49 211 384 240  
Fax: +49 211 384 241 0  
E-mail: poststelle@ldi.nrw.de

It informs and monitors compliance with data protection regulations in North Rhine-Westphalia (NRW). Honestly customers have the right to contact this authority directly if they suspect a privacy breach or have questions regarding information access.

Contact person for data protection

For questions about the collection, processing, or use of your personal data, information, correction, blocking, or deletion of data, and revocation of granted consent, please contact our data protection officer, Dominik Fünkner, at the following e-mail address: datenschutzbeauftragter@datenschutzexperte.de.
